Devesh Sharma

Email: sharmadevesh360@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/devesh-sharma-992661180/

Mobile: +91 8619431049

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate UI Developer with a rich experience of **2+ years** of experience and expertise in HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript and ReactJS. Easily able to pick up new technologies and work on complex UI applications. I can work both as a team player and individual contributor. I love to experiment with new Frontend technologies and libraries. I enjoy solving algorithmic problems and puzzles.

EXPERIENCE

Navi Technologies, Bengaluru- Ul Developer

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

- Created a responsive affiliate partner web application which runs in apps and websites such as Amazon, PhonePe, Swiggy, MakeMyTrip, Zepto, Flipkart etc.
- It is a source of ~500 personal loan disbursals with a whopping revenue of more than ₹3 crore per day.
- Single handedly took the project to the end stage, from project setup (NextJS) to development to deployment while maintaining the best coding practices.
- Integrated Sentry for error tracking
- Integrated Appsflyer events for affiliates
- Integrated MSW for seamless API mocking
- A key contributor and maintainer of the internal Web UI Library used by more than 10 teams and reduced the development time by ~50%
- Creating pixel perfect UI components with pitch perfect CSS
- Writing extensive test cases for the components with 100% coverage
- Ensuring design sign off for new components
- Ensuring best coding practices in the team and guiding other developers both Junior as well as Senior

HDFC Life, Mumbai- Frontend Developer

JULY 2021 - MARCH 2022

- Worked on the following technologies: ReactJS, Redux and Material
- Worked on multiple Insurtech web applications Buying journey(Life
- Easy), Claims, Tele medical(TM)

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- HTML/CSS
- Javascript/Typescript
- ReactJS
- Redux
- Material UI
- Problem Solving

EDUCATION

BITS Pilani, Pilani Campus - B.E. Mechanical

JULY 2017 - MAY 2021

Overall CGPA - 8.23/10